Jeffrey Sean Wilcox

408.859.3003 Pacifica, CA 94044 jeffwilcoxster@gmail.com

Objective

Collaborative innovation leader building progressive web applications, data driven dashboards, online games, and interactive video experiences using the best suited development methodologies. With more than 17 years of experience in agency, corporate, and startup environments as engineer, architect and development director I have a great passion for bringing out the best in every team.

Work Experience

Sr. Software Engineer, MOPO Life

11/2022 – present

- Prototype new user interface for speculative ChatGPT conversational assistant using streamlined iteration and feedback cycles under a tight deadline.
- Troubleshoot CORS access restrictions and provide guidance to backend team for optimizing API responses.
- Development and unit testing new components for user interface improvements using React Native.

Software Engineer II, Twitter (acquired CrossInstall, May 2020)

5/2020 - 7/2022

- Collaborated with design and product teams to ensure Photoshop mockups for new advertising formats were feasible to build as HTML, CSS, and Javascript using internal development libraries.
- Prototyping new responsive ad formats for Twitter using React.js components with Flow static typing, EnzymeJS test coverage, and GraphQL.
- Led sunsetting of standalone playable ads developed for Chartboost, Tapjoy, AdColony, SnapChat, Twitch, Unity, IronSource, Facebook, Google after CrossInstall acquisition.
- Consultant for IAB SHARC draft and JS bridge integration for running playables within Twitter app.
- React.js development for Mopub dashboard UI using Feather component library and TestCafe headless browser automation prior to 1.05b AppLovin purchase.
- Streamlined Mopub client metric reports generation building new dashboard UI with Symphony Php, CentOS VirtualBox, MySQL, Redis, Twig HTML templates & Bootstrap UI.

Engineering Manager & Creatives Team Lead, CrossInstall

7/2016 - 5/2020

- Hired, mentored, and trained external contractors and internal engineering team for diagnosing/ resolving technical problems related to creative development while introducing new features, templates, tools, and game formats. Established multi-faceted playable QA automation.
- Maximize MRAID version compatibility and developed support for new ad exchanges (including Chartboost, Tapjoy, AdColony, SnapChat, Twitch, Unity, IronSource, Facebook, & Google UAC)
- Generated ~\$500k/mo revenue leasing the company's existing creative catalog for non RTB use.
- Architected and evaluate proof of concepts for new pre-play game features and templates which accommodate faster rendering (FPS) when served to mobile devices with limited system resources.
- Automated building and deployment process unique iterations of a playable via internal dashboard.
- Implemented error logging system for collecting statistical data on the type of JS errors occurring most frequently on live MRAID interstitials executing within third party SDK environments.
- Worked with design team to ensure mockups were feasible to implement in HTML, CSS, and JS.

Senior Web Developer, Basis, An Intel Company

11/2015 - 7/2016

- Restructured corporate website using React.js components and ES6 functional programming to optimize flexibility, shorten page loading times, and reduce future maintenance costs.
- Launched eCommerce sales functionality and setup coupon campaigns for specific products being sold. Used Flux application architecture to customize shopping cart checkout experience.
- Collaborated with design and marketing teams to quickly implement responsive holiday promotions from Photoshop mockups, scale website infrastructure, and develop custom templates giving nondevelopers greater control over page content.

- Improved international testing process using a remote VPN so site translation errors can be immediately identified and corrected prior to launch.
- Automated preprocessing, bundling, transpiling, and minification of source code using Gulp and Babel running under Node.js. Standardized team's stylistic consistency using ESLint.
- Setup database migration process for syncing remote Wordpress databases from live, staging, and development environments.

Director of Creative Technology, San Francisco, Flashtalking Inc.

7/2013 - 10/2015

- Developed arsenal of highly profitable HTML5 ad formats marketed to top-tier clients including the parallax expand framework, responsive full-screen interstitial, porthole parallax, browser session cap, IAB adhesion, IAB Filmstrip, 3d cube, 3d flipover and cloth curtain templates.
- Supported internal/external sales and development teams throughout the United States and Europe
 to extend the HTML5 framework functionality based on design mockups, establish best coding
 practices, writing tutorials, and improve troubleshooting.
- Built responsive user interface for Flashtalking's mobile partner questionnaire. Using Bootstrap/ jQuery with a PHP backend, this application streamlined inception of new business relationships based on individual requirements using progressive disclosure, tooltip info overlays, and the ability to save partially completed form submissions.
- Created PHP based page-scraper for harvesting product information from client websites, automated creative conversion process from competitor ads, developed application that allows clients to upload videos into a campaign without re-encoding.
- Independently recruited, mentored, and trained team of less-experienced developers. Wrote numerous wiki articles to share knowledge, gathered collection of mobile test devices, determined in-app troubleshooting methodologies, engineered in-app mobile clickthrough protocols, etc.

Rich Media Engineer, Mediaplex Inc.

5/2010 - 6/2013

- Architected and independently built the MOJO Actionscript Framework Toolkit, a Flash Actionscript plug-in, to streamline the process of building engaging banners for delivery through the MOJO Rich Media platform.
- Collaborated with internal designers to mockup reusable banner templates allowing us to easily configure 100's of highly engaging banner ads by changing the various parameter settings.
- Developed and deployed several custom banner ads for ApartmentGuide.com, iMeet.com, Munchkin which included streaming video, integration with a third-party search API, product carousels, and 3d visual effects following design mockups.
- Independently diagnosed and resolved all rich media ad serving obstacles related to banners received from third party developers.

Sr Media Engineer, Technical Director, DXM Productions

4/2007 - 5/2010

- Evaluated feasibility of Photoshop design mockups and development process for media agency.
- Customized Flexbook component to create interactive microsite book demos for Leapfrog Inc.
- Collaborated with Yahoo engineering team to create streaming Buzzfeed news ticker in AS2
- Built Facebook application for DecisionStreet Inc. using PHP/MySQL, and Javascript
- Created AS3 based product microsites with international localizations for Leapfrog Inc.
- Applied SEO best practices for indexing Flash microsite content in search engines
- Developed AS3 product configurator for Cisco that stores user preferences remotely
- Used PHP GD to dynamically generate data visualizations based on Flickr API
- Implement XHTML/CSS layouts with AJAX functionality using Spry and jQuery

Multimedia Engineer, Design Reactor Inc.

10/2005 - 4/2007

- Developed a series of Flash trivia games for a promotional sweepstakes at Netflix Inc. based on Photoshop mockups
- Created XML based video player and website for Network Appliance, AMD, Universal Pictures based on Photoshop design mockups
- Deployed tracking and metrics analysis to explain user tendencies and traffic variations
- Used MySQL to save threaded video discussions and user registration for Cisco project
- Built dynamic HTML/CSS websites for Loomis & Co. LLP, and Universal Electronics

- Developed HD video player application that displays queue of customers waiting for Apple's in-store Genius Bar using Quartz Composer.
- Sun Microsystems default language cookie set in PHP for translating French and English.

Freelance Design & Programming:

Paul McCartney Digital Library Experience mobile microsite
 Used HTML5 and jQuery to create the mobile version of Paul McCartney's video and photo gallery microsite for iPad/iPhone, Android and WebOS devices.

Touch screen Video Kiosk Applications for Charles Schwab
 7/2011 – 8/2011
 Used Flex 3 to develop custom video player applications for deployment on touch screen kiosk displays in Charles Schwab's office lobby.

Spirit of the Lotus website developer
 7/2010 – 10/2010

 Photographed, designed, and coded custom PHP website with live streaming video of weekly worship service, photo/video archive, and password protected bulletin-board system with rich text editing capabilities.

Art & Design Manager at KSJS 90.5 FM

9/2002 - 2/2003

Designed new online and printed program guide for radio station. Created and designed fliers for advertising the electronic music dept.

Education

San Jose State University

Graduated December 2005

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Digital Media, emphasis on data visualizations and game theory Minor in Business Management GPA for Major Courses (4.0 scale): 4.0

References

Available Upon Request.